teaching.com.au 2019-11-30

# Modern Teaching Aids Privacy Policy

Modern Teaching Aids Pty Limited (' **we** ', ' **our** ', ' **us** ' or ' **MTA** ') is committed to protecting the privacy of the personal information and sensitive information which it collects and holds.

We must comply with the Australian Privacy Principles under the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth). The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to explain:

**(a)** the kinds of information that we may collect about you and how that information is held;

**(b)** how we collect and hold personal information;

**(c)** the purposes for which we collect, hold, use and disclose personal information;

**(d)** how you can access the personal information we hold about you and seek to correct such information; and

**(e)** the way in which you can complain about a breach of your privacy and how we will handle that complaint; and

**(f)** the countries in which your personal information may be stored. 

### 2.1 Types of personal information collected by MTA

#### **(a)** Customers

We collect information from you which is necessary to provide you with goods that we supply (including but not limited to teaching resources and education supplies). This includes collecting personal information such as your name, address, email address, contact telephone number, credit card details, bank account details, and any other information which is necessary to assist us in providing you with our goods. 

#### **(b)** Attendees at Conferences, Workshops and Professional Development Sessions

We collect information from you when you participate in conferences or attend professional development days organised or facilitated by us. This includes collecting personal information such as your name, address, email address, contact telephone number and any other information which is necessary to assist us in developing conferences and professional development to best meet your needs.

#### **(c)** Competition Participants

We collect information from you when you enter competitions either through our website or through competition forms at conferences, workshops and professional development sessions. This includes collecting personal information such as your name, address, email address, contact telephone number and any other information which is necessary to assist us in administering the competition and awarding prizes to competition winners.

#### **(d)** Job applicants

We collect information from you which is necessary to assess and engage applicants. This includes collecting personal information such as your name, address, professional experience, qualifications, references and past employers, and any other information which is necessary to assess your suitability for employment.

#### **(e)** Suppliers

We collect information from you which is necessary to acquire goods or services from you or use such goods or services. This includes collecting personal information such as your name, address, email address, contact telephone number, and any other information which is necessary to assist us to acquire or use your goods or services.

### 2.2 How we collect personal information 

We will usually collect your personal information directly from you which may include whenever you fill out a form on our website; by registering an account with us or use our website using that account; participate in conferences or attend professional development days organised or facilitated by us; and entering in a competition through our website or through competition forms at our workshops, conferences or professional development days. 

Sometimes we may need to collect information about you from third parties, such as credit reporting agencies and past employers and referees. We may be provided with contact lists containing your personal information from a third party such as your company head office, industry associations, industry consultants or state-based education departments provided that we have obtained express consent from that third party to use your personal information.

We will only collect information from third parties where:

**(a)** you have consented to such collection; 

**(b)** such collection is necessary to enable us to provide you with our teaching resources and education supplies; or

**(c)** it is legally permissible for us to do.

We will only collect information which is necessary to provide you with our goods and services, or appropriately manage and conduct our business.

### 2.3 How MTA uses your personal information

We only use your personal information for the purpose for which it was collected by us (' **primary purpose** '), unless:

**(a)** there is another purpose (secondary purpose) and that secondary purpose is directly related to the primary purpose, and you would reasonably expect, or we have informed you, that your information will be used for that secondary purpose;

**(b)** you have given your consent for your personal information to be used for a secondary purpose; or

**(c)** we are required or authorised by law to use your personal information for a secondary purpose (including for quality improvements within MTA).

For example, we may use your personal information for the purpose of:

**(d)** providing our goods (including but not limited to teaching resources and education supplies) to you;

**(e)** notifying you of any of our services and goods of which we consider you may be reasonably interested; 

**(f)** undertaking credit checks as part of our credit application process; 

**(g)** appropriately managing our business, such as assessing insurance requirements and business processes;

**(h)** developing our conferences and professional development programs;

**(i)** administering competitions and awarding prizes;

**(j)** assessing your suitability to work within our organisation;

**(k)** assisting us in running our business, including quality assurance programs, billing, improving our services, implementing appropriate security measures and training personnel; and

**(l)** effectively communicating with third parties, such as courier companies engaged to deliver any ordered goods.

### 2.4 Use of personal information for direct marketing

At times, MTA sends information to market our goods and services which may be of interest to you and may be based on your buying history with us. Individuals can opt out of receiving such marketing materials at any time, by clicking the 'unsubscribe' button in any promotional email sent to you, or contacting the Privacy Officer on the details set out in section 6 below.

### 2.5 Complete and accurate details

Where possible and practicable, you will have the option to deal with us on an anonymous basis or by using a pseudonym. However, if the personal information you provide us is incomplete or inaccurate, or you withhold personal information, we may not be able to provide the services or goods you are seeking, or deal with you effectively. 

We will confine our disclosure of your personal information to the primary purpose for which that information has been collected, or for a related secondary purpose. This includes when disclosure is necessary to provide goods or services to you, assist us in running our organisation, or for security reasons.

We may provide your personal information to:

**(a)** third parties who assist us in managing our business, such as credit report providers, debt collection agencies and professional advisors;

**(b)** third parties contracted to provide services to us, such as couriers, repairmen and technicians;

**(c)** our related bodies corporate;

**(d)** anyone authorised by you to receive your personal information (your consent may be express or implied); and

**(e)** anyone we are required by law to disclose your personal information to. 

### 4.1 Data quality

We will take reasonable steps to ensure that your personal information which is collected, used or disclosed is accurate, complete and up to date.

### 4.2 Storage

All your personal information is stored by us securely in physical or electronic form. 

MTA uses third party data storage facilities that may be located in Australia, the United States of America and Japan. 

### 4.3 Data security

MTA ensures that your personal information is secure by protecting it from unauthorised access, modification and disclosure. We maintain physical security over our paper and electronic data stores and premises, such as locks and security systems. We also maintain computer and network security; for example, we use firewalls and other security systems such as user identifiers and passwords to control access to computer systems.

We keep personal information only for as long as is reasonably necessary for the purpose for which it was collected or to comply with any applicable legal or ethical reporting or document retention requirements.

Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer's hard drive through your web browser (if you allow that) that enables the sites or service providers systems to recognise your browser and capture and remember certain information. Our websites use cookies to anonymously distinguish you from other users of our services and to provide increased functionality when you are using our services. This helps us to provide you with a better experience when you browse our websites and also allows us to improve our websites and our services. Unless you have adjusted your browser settings (where possible) to refuse cookies, our systems will issue cookies as soon you visit our websites or access other services. If you have switched off cookies then some of the functionality of our services may not be available to you. The cookies that we use on our websites only collect anonymous information to optimise our services, and do not collect personal information.

To find out more about cookies including how to disable/enable and delete them at the following website www.aboutcookies.org. If you use your browser settings to block all cookies you may not be able to access all or parts of our sites, or you may experience reduced functionality when accessing certain services.

You have a right to access your personal information which we hold about you. If you make a request to access your personal information, we will ask you to verify your identity and specify the information you require.

You can also request an amendment to any of your personal information if you consider that it contains inaccurate information.

You can contact MTA about any privacy issues as follows:

Privacy Officer   
Modern Teaching Aids Pty Limited   
PO Box 6367   
Frenchs Forest NSW 2086   
Email: privacyinfo@teaching.com.au

If you have a complaint about MTA's information handling practices or consider we have breached your privacy, you can lodge a complaint with:

**(a)** our Privacy Officer, on the contact details listed in clause 6 above; or

**(b)** the Office of Australian Information Commissioner.

We aim to deal with all complaints in a fair and efficient manner.
